我以为我要回越南去
I thought I was going back to Vietnam,
但他们又觉得
but instead they decided
我对付共产党的最好办法
the best way for me to fight the Communists
是打乒乓球
was to play Ping-Pong,
于是我接受了一个特别任务
so I was in the special Services,
走遍全国
traveling around the country,
慰劳负伤的老兵 为他们表演
cheering up wounded veterans and showing'em
怎么打乒乓球
how to play Ping-Pong.
我打得很好 所以几年后
I was so good that some years later,
军队又觉得我应该
the army decided I should be
加入全美乒乓球队
on the all-American Ping-Pong team.
我们是第一批访问中国大陆的美国人
We were the first Americans to visit the land of China
大约一百万年以来
in a million years or something.
有人说世界和平就在我们手中
Somebody said world peace was in our hands,
但我所做的只不过是打乒乓球
but all I did was play Ping-Pong.
回家以后 我成了全国有名的人物
When I got home, I was a national celebrity ,
比袋鼠船长还要有名
famouser even than Captain Kangaroo.
这位就是福雷斯甘
Here he is, Forrest Gump.
在这儿
Right here.
阿甘 请坐
Gump, have a seat.
福雷斯甘 这位是约翰列侬
Forrest Gump, John Lennon.
欢迎你回国
Welcome home.
你能不能告诉我们 嗯
Can you tell us, um,
中国是怎么样的？
what was China like?
在中国大陆…
In the land of China...
人们差不多什么都没有
people hardly got nothin'at all.
没有财产？
No possessions?
在中国 他们不去教堂
And in China, they never go to church.
也没有宗教？
No religion, too?
难以想像
Hard to imagine.
嗯 只要你肯试着想像 迪克
Well, it's easy if you try, Dick.
几年以后
Some years later,
那位从英格兰来的好年青人
that nice young man from England
他回家去看他的孩子
was on his way home to see his little boy
半路上在给人签名
and was signing some autographs.
完全没什么原因
For no particular reason at all,
有人枪杀了他
Somebody shot him.
他们给你…
They gave you...